[
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A massive guard.",
            "job": "To guard of course.",
            "heal": "Quite.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.",
            "answer2": "One life for many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Understand my dilemma?",
            "yesanswer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 40,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 19,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Merida",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wandering tinker.",
            "job": "I seek the wisdom of the shrine of sacrifice.",
            "heal": "Been better.",
            "keyword1": "SHRI",
            "keyword2": "MANT",
            "answer1": "But first I need the mantra!",
            "answer2": "I am told that a hidden shepherd knows the mantra.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye the mantra?",
            "yesanswer": "Good!",
            "noanswer": "The shrine is on a lake to the east!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 40,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Azure",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tinker at the table.",
            "job": "I carve runes.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "RUNE",
            "keyword2": "SACR",
            "answer1": "I carve runes for passage into the shrines!",
            "answer2": "Ask my sister, Mischief.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek a rune?",
            "yesanswer": "Which?",
            "noanswer": "I see."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 41,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Mischief",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A happy tinker.",
            "job": "This and that.",
            "heal": "O.K. I guess.",
            "keyword1": "THIS",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "And that...",
            "answer2": "The rune of sacrifice is hard to get. It lies within the fires of the forge!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou the rune?",
            "yesanswer": "Then ask Alkerion of the stone!",
            "noanswer": "Return when thou dost find it!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 47,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 16,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Damon",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A meek shepherd.",
            "job": "I stand here and think.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "THIN",
            "keyword2": "MANT",
            "answer1": "Oh, just about things.",
            "answer2": "Listen to the bard's song for in its verse lies the key!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Can't a man just think to himself?",
            "yesanswer": "Well I hope so!",
            "noanswer": "Oh, yes I can thou bandersnatch!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 34,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Singsong",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A cute bard.",
            "job": "I sing songs!",
            "heal": "Very well indeed!",
            "keyword1": "SING",
            "keyword2": "SONG",
            "answer1": "I sing songs!",
            "answer2": "Very well, the raven sings, the raven saw and in the corn he sayeth 'CAH'.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou like it?",
            "yesanswer": "Thanks.",
            "noanswer": "Too bad..."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 41,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shentis",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A rotund tinker.",
            "job": "I welcome thee unto Minoc, city of sacrifice!",
            "heal": "OK.",
            "keyword1": "SACR",
            "keyword2": "VIRT",
            "answer1": "Self-sacrifice is a needed virtue!",
            "answer2": "Avatars strive to be virtuous.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou strive for virtue?",
            "yesanswer": "Then perhaps thou shalt become an avatar!",
            "noanswer": "An avatar thou art not!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 90,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Alex",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A teenage boy.",
            "job": "I give out flowers. Here you are!",
            "heal": "Fine, thanks.",
            "keyword1": "FLOW",
            "keyword2": "KIND",
            "answer1": "The way I figure it, if thou art kind to others they will have reason to be kind in return!",
            "answer2": "Yes, give all that thou can unto the needy!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou give?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Alas."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 45,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Mike Ward",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stocky ranger.",
            "job": "I am trying to get a room.",
            "heal": "Well enough.",
            "keyword1": "ROOM",
            "keyword2": "SKAR",
            "answer1": "I have travelled clear from Skara Brae.",
            "answer2": "The rune of our city is missing!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know thee of the rune?",
            "yesanswer": "It is the key to the shrine of spirituality!",
            "noanswer": "It is not in Skara Brae."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 10,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Alkerion",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An old ragged man.",
            "job": "I am a peasant, I hear many things.",
            "heal": "I am old and weak.",
            "keyword1": "HEAR",
            "keyword2": "STON",
            "answer1": "What does thou wish to know?",
            "answer2": "The stone of sacrifice is orange in color and used in the altar rooms of love and courage!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Seeketh thou?",
            "yesanswer": "Good luck.",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 26,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Jude",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A ragged soul.",
            "job": "To redeem myself!",
            "heal": "Ailing.",
            "keyword1": "REDE",
            "keyword2": "SKUL",
            "answer1": "I will not speak of my sin!",
            "answer2": "I used it!",
            "yesnoquestion": "If I help thee wilt thou swear to only use it at the mouth of the abyss to destroy it?",
            "yesanswer": "It can be found at lat-P'F\" long-M'F\" on the darkest night!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 64,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Gimble",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A fading man.",
            "job": "I shall die soon.",
            "heal": "I am barely conscious.",
            "keyword1": "DIE ",
            "keyword2": "CONS",
            "answer1": "I suffer from a tsetse byte!",
            "answer2": "I will soon sleep forever.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Could thou spare a gold piece so I may buy a last drink?",
            "yesanswer": "Remember Azure knows of the rune!",
            "noanswer": "I am saddened."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 90,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Linda Sue",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A small muddy girl.",
            "job": "I'm an undernourished beggar girl.",
            "heal": "I am hungry.",
            "keyword1": "HUNG",
            "keyword2": "FOOD",
            "answer1": "I have not eaten in days.",
            "answer2": "Oh, thou art a kind soul!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Could thou spare a nibble of food?",
            "yesanswer": "I would greatly appreciate that.",
            "noanswer": "Oh, I see."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 88,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Bob the Beggar",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A sickly little man.",
            "job": "I have none, help me.",
            "heal": "I am very sick, help me!",
            "keyword1": "HELP",
            "keyword2": "SICK",
            "answer1": "I need money to cure my sickness.",
            "answer2": "I have terminal leg rot.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou any money?",
            "yesanswer": "Then please share it with me!",
            "noanswer": "Then join me and we can beg together!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 41,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Zircon",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A seasoned blacksmith.",
            "job": "I forge weapons.",
            "heal": "Quite well.",
            "keyword1": "WEAP",
            "keyword2": "MYST",
            "answer1": "I make the very best!",
            "answer2": "Ah, yes, the mystic weapons, and armour, my greatest work! Those I gave unto Sir Simon and Lady Tessa.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Seek thee a weapon?",
            "yesanswer": "Ask at the counter!",
            "noanswer": "Hmmm."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 41,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Julia",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "An agile tinker.",
            "job": "I care for the poor.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "CARE",
            "keyword2": "POOR",
            "answer1": "Self preservation is the first law of nature; self sacrifice the highest rule of grace.",
            "answer2": "Within this house are many poor and destitute souls.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou help?",
            "yesanswer": "I would join thee.",
            "noanswer": "Bum."
        }
    }
]